marcusahayes@outlook.com (318) 497-5373 www.linkedin.com/in/marcus-a-hayes

Software Engineer with 4-year degrees in Computer Science & Economics & 2+ years of experience developing & supporting APIs, dashboards, & microservices within an Agile Scrum framework.

Focus of current work involves the development & support of infrastructure-provisioning automation in a hybrid cloud

Focus of current work involves the development & support of infrastructure-provisioning automation in a hybrid cloud environment

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF NORTH CAROLINA AT CHAPEL HILL

Aug 2018 – Dec 2021

Computer Science, B.A. & Economics, B.A. | GPA 3.67

- Made UNC Dean's List for past 3 consecutive semesters
- Worked & studied abroad in Barcelona, Spain for Spring 2020 semester

EXPERIENCE

CISCO SYSTEMS, INC – Research Triangle Park, NC

Multinational tech conglomerate with a focus on cloud, networking, and cybersecurity solutions

Software Engineer Developing microservices for facilitating infrastructure-provisioning workflows

- Composing thorough & descriptive client & provider documentation
- Supporting developed applications through frequent bugfixes, features, and on-call support

Software Development Intern

May 2020 – July 2020

Created an interactive chat-bot for generating predictions of process execution times

May 2021 - Aug 2021

Jan 2021 - Present

- Partially-migrated a permissions-requesting application to a microservice-based architecture
- Developed web application for auditing ~\$200m worth of transaction data & handling errors daily

SENSING EMOTIONS & KNOWLEDGE GROUP - Barcelona, Spain

Jan 2020 – Mar 2020

Technology startup specializing in cloud-based user experience & playtesting analytics

Software Development Intern

- Articulated optimal methods for play-test feedback communication via informational articles
- Developed biometric processing functions, primarily using the FFMPEG API in JavaScript

UNC-CHAPEL HILL ITS- Chapel Hill, NC

Oct 2018 - Dec 2019

UNC's on-campus IT support for students, faculty, & affiliates

Customer Service Representative

- Diagnosed, resolved, & documented an average of 5 technology issues per hour
- Demonstrated solution processes to clients in a descriptive & simple manner
- Received 4.85 out of 5 average rating in post-service customer surveys

SKILLS & CERTIFICATIONS

- Well-versed in Python, GoLang, & JavaScript/TypeScript programming languages, basic knowledge of C
- Proficient understanding of CI/CD, microservice, and orchestration technologies (Docker, Jenkins, Kubernetes, Argo Workflows)
- Practiced in Agile Scrum development methodologies and technologies (JIRA Align, JIRA Cloud)
- Excellent written & oral communication skills